THEME SONG: In the
not-too-distant future--
next Sunday, AD-- there
was a guy named Joel,
not too different
from you or me.
He worked at Gizmonic
Institute, just another face
in a red jumpsuit.
He did a good job
cleaning up the place,
but his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space.
We'll send him cheesy movies,
the worst we can find.
La la la.
He'll have to sit
and watch them all,
and we'll monitor his mind.
La la la.
Now keep in mind,
Joel can't control
where the movies begin or end--
La la la.
--because he used
those special parts
to make his robot friends.
Robot roll call--
Let's go.
Cambot!
Pan left.
Gypsy!
Hi, girl.
Tom Servo!
What a cool guy.
Croooow!
He's a wisecracker.
If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes,
and other science facts--
La la la.
Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show,
I should really just relax for
Mystery Science Theater 3000.
-OK, Gypsy, if you
had your druthers,
what would your name be?
-Stockard Channing.
-Stockard Chan-- what?
-Oops.
-Oh.
Looks like we're
back on, everybody.
Wow.
Check it out, welcome to
the Satellite of Love.
We're just talking about
if we had our chance, what
would our favorite new name be.
Crow?
-My name is Jose Jimenez.
-Tom Servo, what do you want?
-Well--
MAGIC VOICE (OFFSCREEN): 15
seconds to commercial sign.
I've always liked
the name Magic Voice.
-Oh, I could see-- huh?
-Anyway, Tom Servo?
-Oh, personally, I've always
been partial to Sugar Magnolia.
-Sugar Magnolia.
MAGIC VOICE (OFFSCREEN):
Commercial sign
in five, four, three,
two, commercial sign now.
-And from now on I'll be
known as Chuck Woolery.
We'll be back in two
minutes and two seconds.
-Open.
-Joel?
-Yeah, Crow buddy?
-Would it be OK if I changed my
name to Alan Parsons Project?
-They call me Mr. Tibbs.
-Mrs. Richard Baseheart!
Mrs. Richard Baseheart!
MAGIC VOICE (OFFSCREEN):
From now on,
I'll be known as Vivian Vance.
-That's it, that's it.
From now on, all bets are off.
From now on, we go
back to the old names
for the rest of the experiments.
The Mads are calling.
-You know, Clay, when you
come right down to it,
I think I'd like to be
known as just Frank.
-Why's that, Frank?
-Because if you can't
find peace within--
-Oh shut up.
I went along with
you long enough.
This Mike Douglas furniture
was a terrible idea.
-Don't I get to be your
co-host for the week?
-No, and you don't get to sing
"The Man in My Little Girl's
Life," either.
Oh, hello Booby.
How did you fare going
through the asteroid belt?
-Jeepers, don't remind me.
Ouch.
Well, my invention
exchange this week is--
-Wait for it.
Wait for it.
-Daddy, there's a boy outside.
His name is Tom--
-Shut up.
Now.
-Everybody knows smoking
kills, but it's cool.
What are you doing to do?
Everybody loves tar,
sure, who doesn't?
But scientists have known
for well over a year
that it's bad for you.
So when you go into a
restaurant and they ask you
for smoking or
non-smoking, do what I do.
-Hey, it's a smoking jacket.
Get it?
-Ah, cool.
Like father, like son.
Think about it, won't you?
-(Coughing).
-Yeah, right.
Well here it is, Dimples,
the latest craze--
robotic arm wrestling!
[Whistle toot]
-Ow!
[Pained grunting]
-Frank!
Frank!
Whoo-hoo!
[Grunting]
-Shut up!
Shut up!
-Forrester!
Forrester!
Dr. Clayton Forrester!
Whoo!
[Grunting]
-Yes!
Yes!
[Whistle blows]
-(WHOOPING) Ah, well, your
experiment this week, Joel,
is a bit of a break for you.
It's, uh, I haven't
seen the whole thing,
but it's kind of
a buddy picture.
I've seen the opening
credits, and it
looks to be like a modern
day "Defiant Ones."
Isn't that right, Frank?
-I think you're
going to like it.
It's a little thing we like
to call "Cave Dwellers."
-Frank!
Enjoy it while it
lasts, Astro Boy Toy.
[Alarm sounds, joel
and robots shouting]
-Come on, you guys.
-Oh, this must be in
shoe box format, here.
-How much Keeffe is
in this movie, anyway?
-Miles O'Keeffe.
-Hey, now look here, you can
actually see the driver turn
and shoot Kennedy.
-Cave Dwellers, wasn't he in--
-Cave, Cave Dwellers.
It's the name of the movie.
I'm guessing.
-Hey, Jodie Foster's sister.
I'd shoot Donald Reagan to
prove my love for Lisa Foster.
-I see it.
-Borromel, the thorough,
but gentle laxative.
-Hey, isn't this the
scene from "Brian's Song"?
-Yeah, that's Billy Dee
Williams and James Kahn.
I love Brian Piccolo.
When you hit your knees tonight,
ask God to love him, too.
-Hey bro, let's go get a brew.
Come on.
-David Cain Haughton.
Wasn't he an assassin?
-No, you're thinking
of Lee Harvey Oswald.
-No, it was James Earl Ray.
-No, Mark David Chapman.
-No, John Wilkes Booth.
-No, it's Arthur Bremmel.
-Huh?
-Arthur Bremmel?
-Oh.
-Director of the top
half of the photography.
-There it is.
-Wow, a lot going on back there.
You guys should check it out.
-Hey look, Rusticelli.
That's good with a
little pesto sauce
and some sun-dried tomatoes.
-Look at those poor bastards.
-This is ridiculous.
-Oh, oh, I thought
it was over there.
-Turning a page on
the-- hey, John Newman!
We can put his spaghetti
sauce on the Rusticelli!
-That's good.
-Poor guy.
-The hills have eyes, but
they have glaucoma right now.
[Humming along with
background music]
-That was a close, friend.
[Still humming]
-This week on Cave Dwellers.
-Ugg, I'm grinding the basil
and adding some Romano cheese.
[Slurping sounds]
-Mm, Grog taste good.
[More slurping sounds]
-Hey, it's the cast
party for "Cats"!
It's Betty Buckley, and
she's eating Dick Van Patten.
A little stringy.
-You know, you can eat up
the floor of this cave.
In fact, they're
doing it right now.
-After the fiery, chaotic
creation of the Earth,
in the turbulent period
of man's ascendancy--
-Hey, who's talking?
---the world was populated by
wild, cruel, and ignorant men.
-Oh, you mean the '80s.
-But there are
still a few who seem
to have been touched
by some higher power.
-And they're in AA now.
-Get out of the fire.
-But their table
manners needed work.
-Playing the center spear, Agg!
-Playing defensive backup, Oog!
-And at right
hunchback, it's Org!
[Singing and whistling]
-Hey, there's a
monolith outside!
-Yeah, everybody's
evolving and stuff!
It's really neat!
-Hey, Grog just threw
a bone in the air
and it turned into a spaceship.
-Come on, come on!
Cro-Magnon!
-Neanderthal!
-Australopithecus Africanus!
-Why you--
-Come on, get in a
line, get in a line.
The "Time Life"
photographer is here.
-Hey, it's the Gorgeous
Ladies of Wrestling.
Oh.
-Hey, how can I whose
side-- who's on whose side?
-Oh, it's uh, shirts and skins.
-Oh.
Skins.
-Eat it boy, eat it!
-Ooh.
-Oh, it's the man who
invented the wedgie.
[Applauds]
-Isn't that nice?
-It's an early version
of "West Side Story".
Uhh, I just met
a girl named Uhh.
-Stately Wayne Manor.
-Wow, it's Barbi Benton.
-Hef?
We're all out of Evian.
-You called me, Father?
-Are you still here?
-What's the matter?
-Um, I'm all out of blue stuff.
-I've never seen you
looking so worried.
-Or so ashamed.
-Last night, I had
a strange dream.
-About a chick in
a black bikini.
-It troubled me greatly.
Human knowledge, even in
its most exalted form,
is nothing against fate.
Come over here, my dear.
-Where the camera moved to.
-Over here.
Come on.
[Whistles]
-Hey.
-Father dear, you've always
shared your knowledge
and intentions with me.
Is there something
you've discovered
that you've been hiding from me?
-I've always wanted
you to be wise.
-But we'll settle on looks.
-But remember that imagination
is as important as knowledge.
-Oh?
-Yes, imagination.
-Oh.
-And this you possess by nature.
The next most important thing--
---is peanut butter.
-But this, man learns only
with the passage of time.
-More than you.
-I've waited until now
to show you my discovery.
-A rear view mirror?
-Stronger than dirt.
-It is everything and nothing.
-Uh, could you be a
little more vague, please?
-It's life and death.
Goodness, riches.
-And badness.
-Poverty, and evil.
-It's boss!
-It all depends on man.
-What are man's options?
-What man does with it.
-Then it might--
might be a weapon.
-Exactly.
And like all weapons, it must
be kept away from ambition men.
-And Nazis.
-But Father, how can I save it?
-No, daughter, your
hands are too weak.
-You'll get fingerprints
all over it.
-And Zor's thirst for
power is too strong.
-He's spreading south
with his henchmen.
-I know.
-I see myself in there.
-But he would never dare
to enter our territory.
-I wonder if it's worth the
risk of counting on that.
-Or the risk of acting.
-But Father, you taught me
that science is always a risk.
-Ah, but a man of science
takes a calculated risk.
Science is only a
means, one of many.
-There's also fan dancing!
-Ooh!
-What do you, the
viewers at home, think?
-I'm now too old for so
great a responsibility.
-And for such flashy
jewelry, whoa.
-What do you intend doing?
-To protect a thing
of such great import--
-Tense.
---there is only one man.
Ator.
-But he's a baby.
-Ator is the son of Torin.
He was born during the tenebrous
era of the spider kingdom.
-Wow, everybody did
drugs then, I guess.
---black knights in the service
of Dakkar and his [INAUDIBLE]
high priest were sent out to--
-This must be
Ator's home movies.
-Yep.
---former high
priest carried off
the infant Ator [INAUDIBLE].
-Uh-huh.
-This is the part of the film we
like to call "she had to ask."
-Yep.
---who constantly
scoured the land--
-Uh-huh.
---sacrificial victims
of the Spider God.
-Spider God, uh-huh.
-Sweeping down
upon the village--
-Sweeping.
---Ator, now a young
man, [INAUDIBLE],
black knights badly wounded
him and carried off Sunya,
his young bride.
-Getting all this?
-Say.
-Whoa.
-As Ator nursed his wounds--
-I nursed a scotch.
---he swore to rescue
Sunya and crush
the iron-handed rule of Dakkar.
-Who?
-Griba--
-Son of Flogma, keeper of
the seven keys of Pintuzler.
---encouraged Ator, and
taught him the martial arts.
-And Marshall Crenshaw.
Marshall Tucker.
-Things are moving really fast.
-Yeah.
-Enjoy it while it lasts.
-Hey, Jean Kasem!
-When Ator was deemed ready
to set out for his mission,
Griba revealed the
youth's noble heritage
and consigned to him
the sword of Torin.
-No, the Shroud of Turin.
---only Ator--
-Jeez, Tolkien couldn't
follow this plot!
-It's the wango ze tango!
-Whoo!
-Get down.
-Before Ator could conquer
the Spider Kingdom,
he came under the spell of
the beautiful witch, Indun.
-Ooh, Cher at the funhouse.
-A thousand year
old enchantress,
who called forth a horrible
army of walking dead for slaves.
-It's the Aztec Mummy!
-Ooh, how graphic!
-Wow.
-Check me out, I'm not half bad.
-Captured the glistening
charmed shield of Murdor.
-And the secret decoder ring.
-Oh come, those Moon Boots
went out in the '70s.
-At last, Ator
confronted Dakkar.
-Played by Tommy Chong.
-His gruesome, deformed warriors
in a battle to the death.
-Oh, he's been gonged.
-Aided by the incredibly
potent shield of Murdor--
-And its free prize inside!
---the vicious priest,
then had to kill Griba,
who had revealed his evil
designs for obtaining
power by using Ator as his pawn.
-Then he broke
for a light lunch.
-After rescuing
Sunya, Ator faced
the immense, hideous
spider itself,
and plunged the sword of Torin
into the grisly creature's
body.
-He'd never killed that
big a puppet before.
-When the spider god was killed,
the forces of blackest evil
were unleashed.
-Uh, objects in shield are
smaller than they appear.
---its molten magma in anger.
-Then he worked out on
the charismatic Soloflex
of Zontar 13.
-Now rest, you've deserved it.
-Later, when Sunya died, Ator
retired to the eastern land,
where he lives in
the company of Thong,
an oriental warrior and sage.
-Played here by Jimmy Carl Black
of the Mothers of Invention.
-Eee.
Eee.
-Oh, I hate that.
-That's enough for now, Thong.
-Uh, scratching, that is.
-You know, that exercise
works, you were right.
I can feel it here.
-Wait, where's my shirt?
-The muscles are stronger.
-Are we still in a flashback?
-Uh, I think so.
I don't know.
-Cato?
-He used to be a
teppanyaki chef.
Ha, still using that old move.
-[IMITATING FIGHTING SOUNDS]
Hikeeba!
-You should see him
with vegetables.
-Ok.
Oh, not done yet.
[Fight sounds]
-Then they do improv exercises.
-Align the vertebrae,
and release.
-And break.
-Shake it out.
-There.
That'll do it.
-Now where was I?
[Inaudible]
-Father.
[Surprised gasp]
-Yes, my dear?
-Tell me.
-Again?
No!
-All right.
-Daughter.
You know you're
the only person--
-Oh, I know what's going on.
---recognize the
urgency of my call.
-But I can't leave you
at a time like this.
-During a flashback?
---dear, you will find with
the passing of time that you
can't always have what you want.
-But if you try
sometimes, you just
might find you
get what you need.
-But you're the only one I have.
-You and the doc.
-My dear Mila.
-Dear.
-You don't have to
worry about my safety.
-Dear.
-A sly old fox like me knows
how to take care of himself.
These are things a
man has to learn.
-Quit shaking me, Dad.
-And goes on repeating for the
rest of life, unfortunately.
-Stately Wayne Manor.
-What's Wayne Manor?
-That's where Batman
lived before he became
the Dark Knight in
those comic books.
-Oh, they're not comic books,
they're graphic novels.
-Oh.
-Music by the Super
Mario Brothers.
[Grunting]
[Mimicking horse neighs]
-Quit pushing back there.
Ooh!
-Put your swords down,
you're inside now.
-That city's supposed to
be around here somewhere.
-Follow me!
-We are.
-We're trying.
Which-- oh-- that-- oh, OK.
[Clearing throat, whistling]
-Run outside and see
what the trouble is.
Quickly!
-But you--
-Go, I told you.
Be careful.
-[GASPS] Later, later.
Well, better 86 the hooch.
Well, a little nip won't hurt.
[Shouting and grunting]
-Use the hand safety
on the stairway!
-Hey, wait for me!
-Me too!
-Hey, wait up!
Hey, I found some
funny wet clay.
-It's raining men, hallelujah.
-Wee-hoo.
-Dad, tell me another story.
-I should've realized
the time was so close.
-I've read the script.
-You must ride due east
and try to reach Ator.
The road's long and hard--
[mimicking pnuematic
tube hissing sound]
-When you seem to have reached
the ends of the earth--
-Ask for Earl.
---and it seems that nature
herself declines to accompany
you any further on your
journey, then you will
have reached the domain of Ator.
-Canada?
-How can you ask
me to do this now?
-It is not for myself
that I ask, Mila,
but for the welfare
of all mankind.
Go.
-Take a sweater.
And be back by 10!
-Hi.
[Grunting]
-That's my spice rack!
-Aww.
[Grunting continues]
-Dad?
-Stop!
-Huh?
-How dare you lay hands
on him, you mangy dogs!
[Mimicking dog barks]
-All of you put together are not
worth this man's little finger.
-And I mean that from
the bottom of my heart.
-Out!
-Help me.
-You know, that hat has
a slimming effect on you?
-I thought that among
your many virtues,
the first I'd find
was forgiveness.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Perhaps I've not yet quite
acquired total control
over myself.
-Come.
They're only petty soldiers.
They can't approach
your exalted level.
-Oh thanks, but now's
no time to kiss up.
-Life comes to an end.
All levels are the same.
-Really?
-For my own part, I fail
to see why during life--
-Uh-huh.
---we create artificial
distinctions among ourselves,
because all men are born equal.
-Oh, let me get a pencil, I
want to write that one down.
---makes me sick.
I become more and more certain
that my little visit here
is fully justified.
And will be
extremely profitable.
-You can write it
off on your taxes.
-Do you imply that you
are a conqueror who
claims the spoils of victory?
Or are you a common thief?
-Oh jeez, this has more
pauses than a Pinter play!
-Oh, observational humor!
-God, I love "Seinfeld."
-Let's go.
[Movie sounds fade out]
[Laughter]
-Ooh.
-Ah, too tight.
I don't know, Joel,
I don't think this is for me.
-Oops, I lost it.
That's OK.
What do you mean?
You look fantastic.
I could eat you up.
-Oh, an I could
bite that big toe.
-Ooh.
-Hey, now quit clowning.
You know, what we're going
to do is a little more
lucid version of those
really bad openings we saw.
The credits, you know?
-Oh, credits, yeah.
-That is if Cambot will
man the wall of keyboards.
-What do you say?
-Hey, and will you give us
that half screen posterization
effect too, Cambot?
-No, uh, Joel, what are
we supposed to do, again?
-Well, all you do is
we play the characters
we talked about earlier,
and we run around and stuff.
-Right, got it.
Frolic, cavort, parade,
get about the ship,
that sort of thing.
-Joel?
-Yeah?
-Isn't this kind of fruity?
-Gee, I never really
thought about it that much.
-Joel?
It is.
-Well, no matter anyway.
Let's do it again.
You ready, Cambot?
-Music!
There we go.
[Fighting sounds]
-I thought that was pretty fun.
-That was cool.
-She's still looking for
the ends of the earth, here.
-Ends of the earth,
ends of the earth.
I gotta get to the
Ends of the earth,
ends of the earth.
[Screams]
-Ooh, she's in love.
-So the ends of the
earth are this way.
Thank you.
-You idiot, we don't
even have a doe license.
-That way?
Yeah.
-(GASPING) Ends of the earth.
Ends of the earth.
-Let me see, you were
playing a Titleist, right?
-Yep.
-You've got a rotten
lie, lemme tell ya.
-Daddy.
-Uh, lady?
Can we have our arrow back?
Lady!
Oh, Mrs. Lady!
-Hey, why us she limping?
-Cause she's got an
arrow in her chest.
-Oh, I can see-- huh?
-One thing still
puzzles me, Acronus.
-Use the handrails, I
invented them for a reason.
-Why eastward?
Why did your daughter
fly like an arrow
straight towards the sun?
-Oh, good metaphor.
-Of course, I could easily use
torture to make you tell me,
but that would be too simple.
-And too much fun.
-Spoil our little game.
-Yes.
I see.
It's quite obvious
that you're testing me.
You want to verify my
powers of deduction.
-Mmhmm.
-Very well.
Bring me the map.
-And bringing me the
head of Gallagher.
[Bird noises]
[Random noises]
-Welcome to "Death Vally Days".
The driver's either
missing or he's dead!
-Say.
-Made this in shop class.
It's a letter opener.
-It's not perfect yet.
-A Mark VII production.
-He doesn't give a tinker's
damn about anything.
-Hey, did you just turn into
an owl and then back real fast?
-Maybe it was too hot.
It should be enough for now.
You've gotta wait
until it's cold.
-That could take forever.
-Oh help!
-Huh?
-Look out, it's wet
there, I just mopped.
-Ator, help me!
-Prepare everything, Thong.
-With pleasure, my liege.
-Hey, he's washing with Lava!
-The soap?
-Oh no, the real thing.
-It's Marmaduke.
[Panting]
-All right, good.
-OK, let's see.
We've got the cow skin, the
banana leaves, and the dog.
That should be about everything.
-All we can do is pray, although
we haven't thought of any gods
yet.
-Well, it's up to the dog.
-No, Marmaduke, don't use
the triple overhand stitch!
Bad dog!
[Whimper]
-I could be wrong,
but this arrow
might have something
to do with it.
-Yeah, she's OK.
-Boy, look at how
primitive their wet naps
were during the Dark Ages.
-Well, it's a pretty big hole.
I might need another
one of those.
-Got a crazy idea, boss, let's
make a giant cigar out of her!
-Would you quit [INAUDIBLE].
-It is deserted.
Barren.
-It's the best show tune ever!
It's brassy, sassy, it's
a musical humdinger!
-Let's see--
[UNINTELLIGIBLE BABBLING].
Wait a minute.
-Ator!
-This is the Magna Carta!
-So now we have it.
He was another pupil
of yours, wasn't he?
As you can see--
-He's kind of depressed
about his part in this film,
isn't he?
-Many stories have grown up
around this pupil of yours.
-I wish you'd grow up.
-But now the time has
come for me to discover--
-The manchild within.
---the truth of these stories.
-I pledge allegiance--
-This is really amazing.
Why, your knowledge
of surgery surpasses
even that of the great one.
-Who, Jackie Gleason?
-Oh, I'm just tallying
up your bill, here.
-I'm ready to go, now.
-No, you're not going.
I'll decide when you're ready.
-Little missy.
-The journey is long.
-Long journey.
-Once we start,
there'll be no stopping.
-But I explained to you that
my father is in great danger.
-Danger-- how many
a's in danger?
-I understand the dangers
that face all men.
-All men.
-The wise one is very strong--
-Very--
---and will resist.
---strong.
-But his heart is weak.
-Heart is weak.
-That's the reason he sent me.
-Sent me.
What do you think he's writing?
-The script?
-Oh.
-All right.
But you must know this--
-2 plus 2 is 5.
I mean '.
-If you're too weak, we'll
have to leave you behind.
-Thanks for the beer, Gomez.
-But first you must
prove to us that you
are the daughter
of the great one.
-If you can look bored and
speak haltingly, you're in!
-Come with me.
-No, not you, her.
-There she is.
-Too bad Gomez didn't
get a speaking role here.
-Poor guy.
-Go in there.
-Oh, right.
I'm a freshman at a
small Midwestern college.
The small one was
dark with long hair.
-Mila.
-Now sing something
from "Paint Your Wagon".
-If you're really the
daughter of Acronus--
-Kronus Quartet?
---then you will
know what to do.
-Ok.
-Next, on "Current
Affair," women behind bars!
[Humming "current affair" theme]
-Hmm, OK.
Let's see now, there's a
superball, and half a peanut,
and a length of kite string,
and a carpenter's saw.
What would MacGyver do?
-Is this right?
-Mm, mm-mm.
-Wrong.
Cold.
Very cold.
-Freezing.
-Frigid.
Alaska.
-Oh, you're a cute
one, aren't you?
-Getting warmer.
-Warm as toast.
-She made, uh--
-Very warm.
-She's making flash
powder from her own filth.
-Oh, neat.
[Vomit noises]
-Dibs.
-Rats.
-Uh-oh.
-Oh!
-(SINGING) Love, love, love!
Doot-doot-doo!
-They do have a lot of
product to burn off.
-Mm-hmm.
-I suppose she could
have just tried the lock.
-All done?
-Uh, Gomez, don't pass
in front of the actors.
-Please.
-When I left your
father's castle,
he told me that if ever
the geometric nucleus would
endanger the world's peace,
a messenger would come to me
and prove his identity
beyond a doubt.
-You owe me $50 for the door.
-Ancient Chinese secret, huh.
-Well, my dear Acronus, let
me introduce you to Sandor.
-You can call me Sandy.
-He represents, how shall I put
it, the opposite of your pupil,
Ator.
-He looks like Willie
Nelson, doesn't he?
-Sandor has mastered
everything that lies outside
and beyond the forces of nature.
-And he knows Liza.
---those forces which men
believe uncontrollable.
The occult.
-The IRS.
-What do you say to that?
-Many years ago--
-Oh, not another flashback!
-No, no, no, no no.
-It's cool.
---for higher things.
[Snoring]
-Dear God, he's dull.
-Of course, any man who seeks
knowledge and is wise should be
willing--
-See if you can make
him slow down, Joel.
-Who knows?
-Hey.
-[Inaudible].
-Hey up there.
-As you can see--
-Willie Nelson's
a tough audience.
---giving us a
lesson in humility.
Nevertheless--
-Hey, doesn't he
make leather mugs
at the Renaissance Festival?
---and you will see
a flame of defiance.
-(STAGE WHISPER) Say something!
-Line?
Come on, fake it.
-Yes, it is clearly there.
-And that's my only line.
-Sandor, there is someone
I want neutralized.
-Oh!
---eliminated.
-What happened?
-[Inaudible].
-Right away.
At the ends of the earth.
-Canada.
-Couldn't you find a
more convenient place?
-And who is it, sire?
-Ator.
-Gesundheit.
-It's the chalice
from the palace!
-And now, you will witness
the might of my power.
-Got a minute?
-Ooh.
-Whoa!
-Oh.
Yowza.
-Cool.
-Doodily doodily doodily
doodily doodily doodily.
-Thing's getting kind of weird.
-Say, I think your
cape is fabulous!
-They're getting close
to Ridley Scott, now.
-I don't understand.
-We're not surprised.
-Aren't these guys
employed by anybody?
-I think they're just temps
wandering through the forest.
-Hire-a-Thug.
-Uh-oh.
This fog's starting
to obscure the action.
-What action?
-Whose woods are
these, I think I know,
we'll watch these
woods fill up with fog.
-Where's Mila?
-Who?
-Mila!
-Puma!
-She must be lost.
-I say, it's foggy!
-Guys, this isn't funny!
Guys!
-Puma?
-Ah!
Don't do that.
-Did someone say Ator?
Paging Mr. Ator.
[Coughing]
-After exhausting every
possibility, the men move on.
-I knew there was a cave--
-Fred?
Wilma?
Barney?
Echo!
[Mysterious sound]
-Did you hear that?
Listen.
[Mysterious sound again]
-Come on.
-Quick, run with me
friend, towards the danger!
-Boy, wonder how much it
costs to heat this cave.
-They're invisible!
-Oh man, I don't believe it.
They were too cheap to hire
villains in this movie.
-Yep.
-Oh come on, what is this,
a Charlie Callas routine?
-(IMITATING CURLY HOWARD)
Nya nya nya, voort voort.
-Hey, why don't you pick on
somebody your own opacity, huh?
-What is this, a Heart video?
-Yeah, they only show the fat
one from the head up anymore.
-Hey.
-Sorry, that was a little--
-Dad?
Dad?
-Guy.
-Play "Misty" for me.
-So let's recap
the action so far.
-Uh, nothing, really.
-You're right.
Let's move on now.
[Mysterious sound]
-Dad?
-Hey, why do you keep
hitting yourself?
-Dork.
[Shouts]
-Whoa!
Now they're scarier!
Whoa.
-Booga-booga-booga-booga-booga.
-I do this to my dog.
It's really funny!
[Growling]
-Nah, they're not scary.
They're just kind of goofy.
-Like shooting fish
in a barrel, Dong.
-Thong.
-Oh.
-Come on, just kill
it, don't play with it.
Good boy.
-Don't they want their capes?
-No, they'd have
invisible blood on them.
-Oh, I-- What?
-Daddy?
As long as we're here, can
we stop over at the Gap
and gets some 501s?
-Huh?
-Oh, well like, excuse me, have
you seen two guys with capes?
Ew, grody jody.
-No, guy, I don't want
to sample Giorgio.
[Grunting]
-Who are these guys?
Oh, these must be
the cave dwellers!
-That's right, 35
minutes into the film,
and we're finally at
the first plot point.
-Well, there's Syd Field.
-Hey, I hate Clinique,
really, I'm just looking.
-You go there.
I'll go this way.
-Ah, no, no, no, it's walk
softly and carry a large--
-No, no, it's quickly walk
and carry something big.
-Now, I know it's speak
softly and carry a--
-Ah, you're crazy!
You walk swiftly and
you carry a small--
-You carry something, I
know you carry something.
-You're walking and
you're carrying--
-Whoa!
-Thatch?
-Coppola.
-Dad?
-Ojibwa.
-Ojibwa, wait a minute,
I invented a word!
[Indistinct shouting]
-Ugh, rhubarb, caveman, rhubarb.
-I am a noble savage.
-God, I hate Mondays.
-Boo!
-There's that great
Hammond organ sound.
-Now we steal your hubcap.
Get lug wrench.
-Tuesdays are human
sacrifice day at the Sizzler.
-Guy.
-Mmm, barbecue 'em.
-I think Tony Bennett left
that in San Francisco.
-Ooh.
-Here.
It's a little rare.
[Slurping sounds]
-Oh, ugh.
-I want a Barney Clark bar.
-[Sniffing]
-Mmm, something smells good.
-Ugh, cannibal rhubarb.
-Ator comes out of the
hole, around the fire
-Sees his shadow.
-Hey, it's Dr.
Christian Barnard.
-Oh, what do you know.
-Was.
-Hey!
-Hey, they said hey.
-Hey, you know, now this
really is a Heart video.
Heh, with the thing and-- eh.
Ooh, greasy [INAUDIBLE].
-Huh?
You say something, God?
-Oh, she got childproof cap.
-I've got a wonderful,
Grinchy idea.
-Hey, she already has a plate!
She-- she's self-serving.
-Oh, speaking of
serving, we gotta run.
Let's go, guys.
-Oh yeah, we gotta go.
-Oh, the light and
sound spectacular!
-It was just getting cool, too.
-Oh say, Joel, I
have a question.
-Oh yeah?
Yeah.
Ask away, my red friend.
-Well, why is that
these guys in the film
give such fancy pants
names to everything?
-Yeah, like they call a regular
old shield the glimmering charm
shield.
It's like, so stupid, God.
-Well, it's obvious that this
movie has a really low budget,
especially for props, and so
by adding really neat names
to ordinary things, you
can kind of dress it up.
Like it was kind of obvious her
breast plate that the woman was
wearing was actually
an off-the-rack auto
part from Napa, but you can't
very well say hither yon,
there goes the hubcap of the
Plymouth summer set, right?
-But what you could
say is she has
donned the maiden
shield of Bally Seven!
-Exactly, now you're getting it.
-I get it, I see.
If I had a box of ordinary
paper clips, I could say here
is a box of incredibly
bent pieces of wire
used to hold the pressed
wood pulp planes in security!
-Right, now you're getting
it, that's exactly right.
It's just adding extraordinary
names to ordinary things.
It makes it fun.
-Yeah, yeah.
You find the fun and
snap, the job's a game.
Thank you, Mary Poppins.
-Yeah, spit spot, you two.
-Oh, I love to laugh,
long and loud and clear.
Oh, sorry, I digress.
Well, anyway, they give cool
names to TV shows like that,
too.
Like "White Shadow"
could've been called
haloed hoop honkey, or
"Jake and the Fatman",
you could've called
that, um, well.
"Jake and the Fatman".
Yeah, pretty much.
-Do you know what
occurs to me that when
local TV stations talk
about the grand marshals
for their holiday parades?
What they're really
saying is, Gavin MacLeod.
-Exactly.
Oh, I've got one.
A prerecorded segment
that goes into a program
us called a bumper,
and actually, it's
really just-- movie sign!
-Oh wow.
-Oh boy.
-Oh, let's see, he who
reads these words of wit
eats his little balls.
Oh, now that's immature
even for the Dark Ages.
-For a good time, call Dong.
-Thong.
-Huh?
-They're kind of dumb,
they're easy to kill.
The American Gladiators!
-Ah, something dull.
Come towards it, our friend.
-By the stubbing of
my thumb, something
stupid this way comes.
-Uh-huh, just as I thought.
-Checks out.
-Meter man.
-Knock it off up there!
-For a good time,
call-- stupid rock.
Stupid, stupid rock.
-Oh, man.
-Find a way out?
-Stupid rock.
-Good thing you
were here, Gomez,
we would have never
found it without you.
-Huh?
-Dreezle drazzle drozzle drome,
time for zis one to come home.
-So Bob Hope owns all of that?
-Yeah, yeah, we're thinking of
turning it into a nine holer.
-You have failed, Sandor.
-Bad country singer, bad Willie.
---precious time!
If you had all
the magical powers
that you told me you had--
-Again with the finger!
-I don't see how I failed.
-You don't, eh?
Well, you soon will.
Guards!
-Hey, Paul Wellstone.
-If after all this time Sandor
has been worthy of your esteem,
then you are as guilty of
having failed as he is.
-Flog him!
-Thank you, sir.
-Please, have mercy.
-I fear for you, Sandor.
Mercy does not dwell
in the hearts of those
without spiritual
strength and wisdom.
-Oh, bite me, it's fun!
-Very well.
Imprison him.
I'll employ some tricks
of my own against Ator,
and you can use your time to
come up with something new,
and it better be
good, Sandor, if you
want to regain my esteem.
And I think you know how
important for you is my esteem.
-OK, OK, I'll do linking
rings, I'll do ball in the cup,
I'll do metamorphosis,
wait, wait!
-I'm scared.
Oh, we're already there.
-It's much too quite here.
-Too too quiet.
-Not a good sign.
-I sense the presence
of something evil.
-That's you.
-Zor must be at work here.
-Since we left the
caves, I've had
the feeling that
we're being followed.
-Uh, that's me, boss,
I'm right behind you.
-I don't know, but
we'll soon find out.
-Quick, hide.
-Oh no, they've jumped right
in into a Kurosawa film.
-So it'll start making sense?
-Mmhmm.
-Toshiro Mifune, right there
-I'm huge!
Dig me.
-Yeah.
-Oh no, a mime.
-Did he mention he's huge?
He does that.
-Warriors, come out and play!
-No, you see, I used two blades.
The first blade lifts the
head away from the body
before the head can snap back.
And then, bluh-- below
the skin level, yeah.
-We get it.
-Come on, come on!
-Ooh, right in the bread basket.
-You know, the reason
this scene is so good
is because we care
about the characters.
-We do.
-I mean, we do?
-We really do.
-Hey, it's the
life of the party,
he's got a lampshade
on his head.
-He'll be the death
of the party, soon.
-Wicker armor,
courtesy Pier One.
Doesn't work too well,
it's just decorative.
-Hurts, don't it?
-Look out, its
Koko the Terrible!
[LAUGHS] Goofy old mime.
-Oops.
Ouch.
-OK, just like we rehearsed it.
Over, cross, ha ha!
I will kill you!
-Oh.
-Or not.
-Hey, is this where
the kegger is?
We stalled Mark's van in front.
-No, wait.
-Uh, we just remembered,
uh, we didn't
leave enough change
in the meter.
We're double parked!
Bye!
-No use chasing them.
Save your strength.
The castle of the Great
One is still far away.
-And the end of the
movie is even further.
-Well said.
-What I mean is--
-Hey, [INAUDIBLE].
---certain risk
involved for you.
In stopping Ator, I might,
inadvertently, of course,
also harm your daughter.
What do you say to that?
-I say you could drive a
Mack truck through your cues.
Tempo, tempo, pick it up!
-I must admit,
that as a murderer,
you are most impressive.
-But as an Andrew
McCarthy fan, whoo!
-You will receive
nothing from me but pity.
-Careful, old man.
-Go to bed, old man!
-My patience has its limits.
-I'm aware of that fact.
-As does your talent.
-But I mustn't expect
too much from you.
Patience, after all,
is a virtue which
is found only in the strong.
-You're wonderful.
-Marry me.
-You do amuse me.
And provoke me.
-That is love, isn't it?
-What is it?
-Ator has escaped again.
-D'oh!
-Hi, Curt Gowdy here.
Join Thong and Phil Harris
and me out on the Idaho River,
fishing for trout.
-[LAUGHS] Now try
catching a steak, Dong.
-Thong.
-Ator, what's your dream?
-How big is God?
-For a moment back
there, I had the feeling
you knew those men
that attacked us.
Did you?
-Yes.
-Well, we played
varsity together.
-I do.
-Who were they?
-They're the survivors of
the noble tribe of Han.
They worship the
god of war, Soko.
-Soko?
I know that name.
-Oh, he dated my friend Sharon.
---the northern territory.
-Uh, what's Miles sitting on?
-His second in command
was his brother--
-I don't wanna know.
-In a great battle
against the Han,
Zor exterminated them,
but spared the lives
of three samurai,
and then used them
to kill his own brother
to usurp his power.
-Oh, if this is
another flashback,
I gotta go get a sandwich.
-Do you think that Zor will--
-It's OK.
-Do you think my
Father's still alive?
-Oh, sure. [SNORT LAUGHS]
-Zor wants to possess your
Father's knowledge, Mila.
-And your mother's wardrobe.
-And the geometric nucleus.
No, your father's safe
as long as he has it.
-Uh, that's enough fish, Dong,
thank you, thank you very much,
Dong, that's enough fish.
-Just a few dozen more.
-Why did you go and
live so far away?
-Well, it's on the bus line.
-Your father taught me
the path I must follow.
It is for this I
live the way I do.
-But shouldn't a man's destiny--
-Oh, I thought you were
going to say something else.
---coincide with the
desires of his heart?
-A man's destiny is
always predetermined--
-Oh, he's a Calvinist.
---by the true
desires of his heart.
I know what mine is, and I must
follow the lonely [INAUDIBLE].
-I'm sorry, I
didn't mean to pry.
-That's all right,
I'm glad you asked.
-What's your major?
-Thong?
The fish is ready.
-Oh, wow, what I wouldn't give
for a Weed Eater right now.
-Oh no, don't kill us!
-Uh, what will you give me?
-OK, you talked me into it.
-Huh?
What?
Mom?
Dad?
Uncle Dave?
Oh.
-Mila.
-What is it?
-Someone's coming.
Look.
-Cover your hip.
-Get dressed.
-Who are you?
-Uh, we're pirates.
-What do you want?
-Look, you captured us.
-[CLEARS THROAT] Line?
-Where do you come from?
-Everywhere and nowhere.
-Somebody say something.
-Well, answer.
Can't you speak?
-We're from Sulajin.
-Ehhn, wrong answer.
But thanks for playing.
Sulajin?
-Yes, it's to the north,
not far from here.
-Yeah, I worked out there.
-I know.
It's where my parents were born.
-Then you're Ator?
Pupil of the Great Master?
-Yeah, that's me.
Pretty much.
-You may speak
without fear with me.
-Much evil has fallen on
the people of our village.
-Bummer.
-In order to survive,
we must make an offering
to be god of the Kungs.
Humans sacrificed to the
serpent god on every full moon.
-Besides, our people
are not warriors.
We're only poor farmers.
-If we don't get help
soon, we'll all die.
-Hmm, I like it.
Make it shorter, I'll buy it.
-The Kungs have always
demanded the blood of man.
-Ha, yeah, they're
funny that way.
-They'll soon finish you.
We must act quickly.
-But not right now.
In a minute or two.
Half an hour, maybe.
-Wow, check out the way
that guy moves, huh?
-What do you intend to do, Ator?
-We'll take them
back to the village,
and I'll speak
with their people.
-The Village People?
-The Kungs will kill us.
-I think-- we should run!
-Ah!
-No.
Let them go, Thong.
-If you love
something, let it go.
-We'll go without them.
-We'll hurry down there.
---first to volunteer?
-I'll be doing the death scene
from "Camille", thank you.
-And the next?
-Come forward, Cowardly Lion!
Oh, it's a woman.
-I could use a man like you.
And I do mean use.
-Uh, you, uh, never mind.
-Nice try.
-We need another.
-I'll go.
-Uh, no, you went last
time, one to a customer.
---not you my dear.
Our family's already given
one life to the Kungs.
-I must, or else another
will have to take my place.
-Nancy Walker in a cameo role.
-Wait!
-Hey!
It's speedy delivery guy,
and has he got a package!
-Stop!
-In the name of love.
-Just wait for me, I'll
be down in a minute.
Just stand there, I'm coming.
OK, well now-- oh.
I thought this was the
Anderson party, sorry.
I'll just be on my way.
-Who is this gentle
stranger with pecs
like melons and knees of fringe?
-Ator.
You have chosen
a day of mourning
to visit the village
of your parents.
-Afternoon.
-I've come to help you fight.
-We're not fighting them.
The Kungs will massacre us.
-You must.
If you go on like this, none
of you will be left alive.
-Dude looks like a lady.
[Stupid laughter]
-Where's Ravani?
-Who?
-Ravani has left us.
-Because he had nothing
to do with the film.
-He was too old to guide us.
-I have taken his
place as the elder.
-He was a proud, courageous man.
-But dumber than
a bag of hammers.
-He never would have allowed
such submissive behavior.
-What, are you
calling me a wussy?
-You must not lose heart.
I see great courage--
-Because a guy will eat it.
-Most of your young people
willingly sacrifice themselves
to be victims--
-Coffee.
Tea.
[INAUDIBLE] nuts.
---and fight back?
-Soft drinks.
---and I will help you!
You will regain your freedom--
-Juice?
---peace again.
Surprise is an excellent weapon.
-Hi Estelle.
How you doing, Mickey?
---intelligence, rather
than brute strength.
-Posture people.
Let;s snap it up a bit.
---they are stupid as well.
-(WHISPER) That's Gary.
---make frontal attacks
against their enemies.
They know you have
been pacified,
and won't be expecting
any resistance from you.
-Uh-huh.
-What we must do is
prepare a shock for them
when they arrive right
here, and then we'll
take them by surprise.
-The village is well situated.
-And so am I.
-Those rocks will act as
a wall to protect you.
-And vice versa.
-That side is
impassible to horses,
so they'll have to
attack from over there.
To fortify that
exposed side, I'll
need several sharp stakes,
ropes, and three men
to help me.
You, and you two, come with me.
Are you afraid?
-No.
-Won't you fight to
save your people?
-No.
But I will.
I want to fight.
-For my right to party!
-Good.
Who else will join him?
-All done back there?
---more of you here worthy
of being called men?
-Over here, Mr. Ator, yoo-hoo.
-Or are you no
better than sheep--
[bleating]
---not just [INAUDIBLE].
We are a people who--
-We need more Calgon.
---but you have convinced--
-My husband, some hot shot.
-Ancient Chinese secret, huh?
-Ator's prehistoric cave
dwellers and Milwaukee
are a long way apart, but they
have one thing in common-- cave
man means the best
human hears available,
and Milwaukee means sacred wine.
-Now Ator--
-Cream or sugar?
---first, let us
drink to your return.
And then we will
discuss your plan.
-Drink it all, sometimes
the poison's on the bottom.
---village of your ancestors.
May your stay--
-I've heard this part.
-Oh well.
-I thank you and
drink to the health,
prosperity, and liberty--
-Not bad.
-Champagne makes me giggly.
[Giggles]
-But let us organize ourselves--
-I smell a rat.
A big Commie rat.
-I'll need your strongest
men to build defenses.
-It's Timothy Leary!
I guess Liddy will have to
do the tour without him.
-Let's get to work.
-My name is Ravani.
Tell Ator they're
going to trap him.
-Yeah, yeah, get
some sleep, Quentin.
Ok?
Make sure you're drained good.
-Hello?
Your spit bucket's full.
OK, so, I'll just go now, OK?
Do I just leave the sign on
so the maid makes the room?
Ok.
[HUMMING] I'll close the door.
-Are you done with your
[MENACING LAUGH] drink?
-We secretly switched Ator's
coffee with Folger's Crystals.
Let's watch.
-He is huge.
-Timber!
-Oh, right, now we call this
film the Wong Dwellers, aww
yeah.
-Thong.
Yeah, Thong.
Sorry.
-Satellite picture shows
clouds coming in from the west,
but this should burn
off by about noon.
-Before the dawn of time.
A race of druids.
Nobody knew who they were
or where they came from.
-Cool.
-Boy, that cleared
up really quick.
-Yeah, I told you it would.
-We've been betrayed.
-Darn.
-But I'm still alive.
-Think so?
-I wonder if it wouldn't have
been easier if we had just
kept on going to the
aid of my father.
-Oh, Monday morning quarterback.
-No one's life is more
important than another's.
-Except mine.
-Your father would
have done the same.
-Wear a tiny leather bikini?
-This is CNN.
Luke.
-Check it out, they worship
the Munsingwear penguin.
-Now pardon us, did you
see a little tiny fox run
through here?
No?
-The village elder
was the one who
lured you to come to help us.
-In other words, those
two were part of the plan.
-I wish they were
part of the plot.
-Yes.
The others were against
it and wanted to fight,
but the majority
were too terrified.
The elder's going to hand
you over to the Kungs.
In exchange, they've promised
to stop killing our people.
-All right, who's talking?
-I can't figure it out.
-Must be the director.
---allied with Zor.
-And what happened to Ravani?
-The new elder has been
slowly poisoning him
because he knew Ravani
would warn you if he could.
-Fun.
-I think Ravani
must be dead by now.
[Yelling]
-Hey, it's Teddy Roosevelt
and Rough Riders!
-I think it's the Kurds.
-And whey?
-Yes whey.
-They are terrifying,
aren't they?
With those bandanas,
and they all
look very Machiavellian
with their shirts off.
-Machiavellian?
-Hiya Phil.
-Morning, Tom.
-A month has now
passed, old one.
Have you done what you said?
-[INAUDIBLE] we have
kept our promise.
Now you must keep yours.
I give you Ator, but
in return, our village
will no longer have to
sacrifice to your serpent god.
-Uh, that must mean no.
-No, I think so.
[Shouting]
-Grr!
-Yee-hoo!
-Those are the Pillage People.
-No!
-No.
-That's not fair, I'm the
star of the show. [SOB]
-Oh duh, I'm sure.
My hair is getting singed.
Last time I go club
hopping with this guy.
-Honey, start
lighting those huts!
-A job well done.
-No!
No!
Please.
-Looks like back
lot at Universal.
[Gasping]
-Feel the burn, come
on, go for the burn.
-Hey, here's just a wild
idea, why don't you rotate
to the other side of the
pole where the fire isn't?
-This scene brought you
by Kingsford Charcoal.
-Edges light quickly.
-You know, they shouldn't have
filmed this at Yellowstone.
-Yay!
-All right.
Finally.
-Aww.
-It's them again.
-I'll probably rip this out.
It was there when we moved in.
Good foundation, though.
Had a little trouble
with silverfish,
but that's just for a
few weeks in the spring.
-Oh, hiya Phil, how's
the snake hanging?
I love that joke.
-That's a cute story.
-Hey, who's the new guy?
-They're so sad.
-Somebody say something.
-That guy with the beard
really looks bitter.
-I'm the best looking man in
the Middle Ages, my, my, my.
-Hi Fred.
Hi everyone.
Looking good, Simone.
Sorry I'm late.
-Hi.
-Hello.
-What are you looking at?
-Here is the treasure I owe you.
-You can count it, I don't mind.
-And I trust you
will also accept
a little personal offering
from me to your god.
-It's a new car!
Oh.
Sorry.
-The Bangles?
-I want to thank you
for your offering.
Though it wasn't
in our agreement.
-Oh close your robe.
-But do not think you'll be able
to exchange Ator or the girl
for them.
-Darn.
-It will be my honor to
perform the rites of sacrifice
personally.
-I use the word
offering precisely
because I didn't expect
anything in exchange from you.
-I'm trying to say I'm sorry!
-I'll consider our
mutual agreement
to be entirely fulfilled.
-Hi.
How you doing?
-Your father is safe and well.
-In Hell.
-Unfortunately, I won't be able
to say the same to him of you.
-Or of you to him, or--
oh well, never mind.
-All my efforts--
-Don't touch the hair.
I work on the hair
and you touch it.
-It's obvious you're not
cut out for good deeds.
Anyway, it will be less
repugnant to be strangled
by a thousand serpents than
to have to endure your smile.
-I see.
What does repugnant mean, again?
Oh, no matter.
-Yes, well.
You don't find me
repugnant, do you?
-You have defeated my magician.
You have defeated my warriors.
But all your science
has proved helpless
against the powers of
imagination and cunning.
-May I just, uh, cup
one of your pecs?
-[INAUDIBLE] weak point.
-Ding dong.
-Your eagerness for good
deeds has betrayed you, Ator.
The master won't be very
pleased with his prize pupil.
-Tits all over-- I mean
it's all over for you, Ator.
I know we've been
breast-- best friends.
Damn.
-Has the mighty Ator--
-Nipple.
---nothing to say?
-Must be cold in there.
-I have only thing to say.
-Plastics.
-We will meet again.
-Don't know where,
don't know when.
-Your master has
taught me one thing--
the dividing line between
goodness and stupidity
is very, very fine.
-Come on, girls, let's go!
-Begin the sacrifice.
-Oh, wait a minute, the
tape's not queued up!
-I got it.
[Sobbing]
-There's a maraca down there.
-I can't go in there,
Susan Hayward's down there!
-Whoa.
-Oh, all right.
-Uh, am I late?
Uh, hi Travis.
Uh.
-Do I look good or what?
Yes, yes.
-I shall now sacrifice for all
your help and for the powerful
protection--
-Yeah, yeah,
powerful protection.
Yeah, uh-huh.
---as well as Mila, daughter
of Acronus, and Ator--
-Daughter of, uh, OK.
-I pray that these human
sacrifices will please you,
so that you will
favor us, and we can--
-Think of something, Thong!
---your name, mightiest of gods.
-All right, down you go.
[Screaming]
-Hey, this isn't
so bad in here, I
could really get used to this.
-Kind of pleasant.
-Snake problem, though.
-Oh, wait a minute, folks.
We have snakes growling here.
-Just like the other one.
-No, no!
-Hey, what happened
to the first girl?
-Look, I'm way over
here, calm down.
I just ate, I can't eat another
thing for another six months.
You're in great shape.
-Growling again.
-You know, Streep
was up for this role.
-Ha ha, snakes that
growl. [STUPID LAUGHTER]
-The slower and more
painful the death--
-No.
---the more pleased
will be the serpent god.
-You know, he told
me that really
in the strictest confidence.
-All right, throw
down another one.
-Just like the other one.
-Wait, I'm '-F!
Ooh!
-Man, Gomez is really
taking his time.
-Come on.
-Here comes a creepy mouse.
-It's padding.
-No!
No!
[Screaming]
-And now, the fourth victim
to please our omnipotent god!
-Uh-huh.
-No, no, no!
I beg you!
-All right.
-I'll just hide here
behind his chaise longue.
-There.
-Oh, this is a ComfoRest
adjustable bed.
[Screaming, snakes hissing]
-Oh, look, anal
retentive snakes,
they lined up the skulls.
-Shut up, come on!
-I'd like to move that
hair out of his face, jeez.
-Oh, he's taking
her home for later.
-Bye!
-That was neat.
-[Inaudible].
[Screaming]
-In you go.
-Psst, hey Ator.
I'm behind this little
linoleum post over here.
Yeah.
It's cool.
-What's he gonna do?
-Ow!
-Ooh.
-Accept, your lord of
serpents and evil--
-Get your own.
---which we, your
servants offer you.
May your spirit and
strength be transmitted
to us so that we may reign--
-About to cut
through your wrist.
-Now the man.
-I always knew I
would be an apostle.
-Ouch, I landed on
my eight-sided dice.
[Groaning]
-Now her.
-Uh-oh.
-Come on, in you go.
Get in the bidet, sister.
Insy-winsy, come on.
-Aha!
-Ator, look out!
-Here we go.
Now we finally have some action.
All right.
-Let's get busy.
-Oh no, we've got to go now.
Just when its getting good.
Doggone it.
-That's just the
way it is, isn't it?
-Carry me.
-No.
-Chase me.
-I'll kill you myself, Ator.
-Oh, say, Joel.
-Mmhmm?
-Why is it when they punch
each other in this movie,
it doesn't sound
anything like a punch?
-Yeah, it sounds more like
a bag full of sardines
thrown against a pole barn.
-Well you're too far
off, you skipsters.
You see, sound
effects artists use
a technique called foley
to create those sounds.
It's interesting, isn't it?
-Not really.
-I don't think so.
-I think maybe you
should humor me.
-Ok.
-OK, sure.
-Oh, foley, huh?
Interesting.
-Yeah, tell us.
-Well, I'm glad you asked, boys.
Foley artists use a lot
of ordinary items found
around the home or
office to create
convincing sound effects.
-Oh, like the sound of
fists slamming into jaws?
-Right.
But let's get started
with something simple.
An easy way to make
a horse trotting
is to use a pair of coconuts.
-Coconuts?
-Right, now listen.
It's the sound of a
quarter horse gilding
on a cobblestone courtyard.
It's pretty
convincing, isn't it?
-Yeah, but what if
the horse is on grass?
-Oh, you add these
handy sounds muffs, OK?
-Whoa, all of a sudden
we're at Aqueduct.
-Yeah, you can do all kinds
of stuff, like take punches.
-Oh I'd rather not.
-Not in the mouth.
-I mean-- I mean the
sound of punches.
OK, traditionally
a leather glove
against a heavy metals-- or a
heavy punching bag was used.
Heavy metal punching bag.
-Ooh.
-But the sound in this Ator
movie is much, much cheesier.
-Right, I'm way
ahead of you, buddy.
You just use these
goggles here, OK,
and use a pair of Hollywood
meat slammers, OK?
Add your own grunts.
-Real meat!
[Grunting]
-Like that, see?
-That is absolutely perfect.
But why the goggles?
-Eye protection.
Now, I want you to
name me a sound,
and I bet I can foley it.
-I got it, I got it.
Uh, do the ocean.
-OK, that's easy.
Just add bird shot
to a drum head.
-Say, that's cool.
-Yeah, it's neat, huh?
-OK, I got another one.
Let's see.
How about the sound of
somebody's spine cracking?
-Oh that's easy.
You use celery.
Make sure it's fresh.
[Grunting]
-That's too easy, guys,
give me a hard one.
-Oh, OK, I got it.
A herd of buffalo.
-Oh, no problem, box
full of hamsters.
-Poor guys.
-Uh, did I say buffalo?
I meant water buffalo!
-Oh, well that's simple.
You just add some milk.
-Uh-huh.
-Poor little guys.
-Check it out.
-Well, OK, now I
got a tough one.
A rubber Wellington
boot stuck in the mud.
-Oh, that's easy.
You just fill a
pair of pantyhose
with some jello like that.
-Wow.
-Oh yeah.
-See?
It's neat.
-Cool.
-All right, uh, do a scream.
-Oh, well there's a
lot of ways to do that,
but I'll show you this way.
Just take-- for a
man's voice, you just
take an Ohio blue tip match,
strike against somebody.
-Ow!
-See?
Yeah, it's simple.
-OK, now how about a
woman's scream, Joel?
Oh well, then for a woman,
you set fire to TV's Madame.
-Oh, that's easy enough.
-No, don't light my hair, oh no!
Oh, help me!
-There she goes.
-I'm flaming, oh, get me to a--
[interposing voices]
-We'll be right back.
[Shouting]
-Well that was the action.
-Yipes.
-Would be the mother loving--
-[INAUDIBLE] of
all sock puppets.
-Yeah.
You might say he's
coiling a cobra, big time!
-And you know what?
He's not slimy at all.
-That's because he's
made out of velour.
-Yeah, that's probably it.
-A planet where snakes
evolved from men?
-Uh, you know, um, you
can jump in here any time.
No problem, no, I
got it, it's OK.
You just stay doing what
you're doing over there.
It's OK.
-Quick, hand me a hanger.
-Just cut the wires, Ator.
-This is for Kukla.
Yeah, and this one's
for Fran Allison, yeah.
-I'm coming, Beany Boy!
-Well, that was neat.
-Are you all right?
-Oh.
-Oh, you got a cigarette?
-Let's stay up and talk a while.
-I'm spent.
-K2, rising majestically
above the Nepalese highlands.
Or not.
-It's too quiet.
-Too too quiet.
-Is there another
way up to the castle?
-Behind the wall,
there's a secret passage.
Maybe we can slip in unnoticed.
-We'll never free your father
without them knowing it.
-How secret could it be
if he knows about it?
-We'll have to fight them.
-The three of us?
-No, just me.
You were a big help
with the snake.
-Gomez, you wanna
take a line, buddy?
-If I remember correctly,
there's another way in.
-Yes, it's still there.
It opens into the
underground passage.
-It's a super secret
double dog entry.
-You and Thong go in that way.
-Uh, it Dong, sir.
No, it is Thong, isn't it?
-Thong.
-Did you hear something?
I swear I heard something.
-I'll keep them busy outside.
[Maniacal laughter]
-Everything's going
to be all right.
-He must have something in mind.
-So, you live around here much?
Do you?
Oh.
-Oh, come on.
-What the!
[Laughter]
-Terrific.
-I'm the luckiest
boy in the world.
I have slipped the
surly bounds of Earth
and touched the hand of God.
-This is a little ridiculous.
OK, so, he kills a
deer, he tans the hides,
he stretches the skins, he makes
an anodized aluminum frame,
he learns how to
extrude and weld,
all in about five minutes, huh?
Learned aerodynamics.
-Boy, you get up here,
everything looks small!
Only one problem, how do
I get this thing down?
-Yeah, it looks like he
flew into an Omnimax show,
doesn't it?
[Humming along with music]
-He flew into another country?
-(SINGING) Ator flies
and so does my heart.
I'm In his kite made of
string and sticks and bamboo--
[sobbing]
---I fly along with you.
-It's so pretty.
-I go along for the ride.
I'm not stupid like
the rest of them.
-Ator, Ator my sweet friend.
-Huh?
-Oh.
-What?
-Oh, that [INAUDIBLE] crazy.
He's killing me.
-Gomez!
I've invented the wheel!
-Ator Thomas Petersen,
you get down here
immediately this instant!
-It's not just Ator that's
flying, it's the human spirit.
Let's get out of here.
-Help me, I don't know how
to get this thing to work!
Goodbye!
-Goodbye!
-Goodbye folks!
-(SINGING) And he flies
with his stupid contraption.
-I think I just
invented air sickness.
-Meanwhile, at the wineries
of Ernest and Julio Gallo,
Tommy Smothers is
raising quite a havoc.
-Oh, my hub-- my
hubcab's chafing!
-This must be the
secret passageway.
Let's go.
-(SINGING) So high he flies.
-Great, this is the opening
from "Where Eagles Dare."
I've seen this.
-Weyerhaeuser is
committed to preserving
our natural resources.
-I can see my house from here!
-(SINGING) We're flying
so free, Ator and me.
-Hey, and it's anamorphic!
-Huh?
We're in Vienna?
-Hey.
-Hey, look up there!
-What is it, a bird?
-It's bird!
It's a plane!
It's Superman!
-Oh, I've seen that comic.
-It's a graphic novel, Joel.
-Ator, this is George Kennedy.
We're going to
talk you down now.
-You're crazy, it can't be.
Hold on, there's
a man in the sky!
-A man in the sky?
Get out of here,
enough of your lies.
-I think I blew my cover.
-Is that Ator up there?
-Or are you just glad to see me?
-Because I taught him
the theory of flight.
And if you had been a
better student, Zor,
you could be flying, too.
-There's those meat slammers.
-Theory of flight?
I'll teach you the
theory of fist!
-You can go on beating me--
-But knee me in the groin first.
---because Ator is
better than you.
He'll vanquish you.
-We'll see about that!
-Ooh, that one stung.
He hit on that one.
-Connected.
-Made contact.
-(SINGING) Landing music.
He's in trouble.
-Pretty.
-I gotta land, I'm
almost out of fuel.
-Oh, it's an Alpine
White commercial.
-Well, looks like he flew
into 17th century Bulgaria,
and that's Mad Ludwig's
castle right there.
[Spitting sounds]
-Oh, right in the turret.
-Message for you, sir!
[Shouting]
-Oh, he also made bombs while
he was making that kite thing.
-Looks like he's
gonna carpet bomb.
Yep.
Yeah.
-All right, you crummy
rats, Henry Kissinger
says Merry Christmas!
[Whistling]
-Whoa.
-That's for calling me a femme.
-Oh.
-Oh, he didn't even
throw that one.
-Damn, no handrail!
-Oh, that's a nice,
well-lit secret passageway.
-Well, its secret,
but they didn't
want to get carried away.
-Ok.
-Thrust, parry, advance,
cross, thrust, back, thrust.
-Here's one for my
old pal, Melvin Laird!
[Whistle]
-Oh my God, they hit
Charlie McCarthy.
[Spitting sounds]
-Oh, I love this.
This is going to be my
regular Saturday night thing.
-He's his own regular
Saturday night thing.
[Humming along with music]
-I thought the movie was done.
-Oh, he's landing
in the Outback now.
-Huh?
-How'd he do that?
-How'd I do that?
-I suppose he's gotta
tank in the courtyard now.
-Yeah, and it's made
out of coconuts.
-I think I can, I think
I can, I think I can,
I think I can-- uh-oh.
-This is for you.
And here's one for you!
There's a little bit
more for you, thank you.
-Coming through.
-I know the nucleus
is in here somewhere.
And you had better
tell me where it is.
-He's probably tell you if
you'd stop pushing him around.
-Or I will kill you
with my own bare hands.
I'm warning you!
Now tell me, where
have you hidden it?
Out with it, you old fool!
-It's over by the [INAUDIBLE].
You can't miss it.
[Choking sounds]
-[Inaudible].
-If I can't have
it, nobody will!
-Hey, he's gotta cut the
heck out of his thighs
with those swords.
-No, you will die!
-No!
-Ator.
-No.
-Ta-da!
-You can call me
Atra, and I don't
come with a comfort strip.
-I'm not afraid of you.
-Well, maybe a little.
-So, the mighty Ator needs two
swords to fight with, does he?
-Mockery is the
ignorant man's weapon.
[Grunting]
-So, the mighty
long-haired John Saxon
needs two swords to fight.
-Is this the mighty Ator?
-Uh, no, that's a pole.
Oh, wait.
Who's that little [INAUDIBLE]?
-Have you lost your nerve?
-Oh, come on, yeah, he ran
to the ends of the earth,
he invented the wheel,
he's had a long day.
-Hey, look, the "Desiderata"
is on the wall over there.
It's an original.
-Not gonna help him now.
-He's not much without
his hang glider, is he?
-No!
No!
No.
-You have wonderful pecs.
-Made you blink.
-No.
-Hey, is that a comic
book over there?
-It's not a comic book,
it's a graphic novel!
-For crying out loud.
-OK, now that-- that's good.
-Can he do that?
-Now I'll cut you in two!
-Into what?
[Laughs]
-Oh, ouch, owwie,
owwie ow, owwie.
-No, Ator!
You can't!
Zor's disarmed.
If you kill him now,
you'll be guilty of murder.
-What?
-Wait until he is
tried by the high court
of the league of peaceful lands.
-Oh, he's making that up.
-What is this, BC Law?
-They will make him
pay for his crimes.
But for us to take
the law in our hands
puts us on the level
of the barbarian.
-We are barbarians.
-Destroying life
is something man
shouldn't take upon himself.
-What are you, Lucas
Tanner all of a sudden?
-So what the heck did I hang
glide in here for, anyway?
-Could've wrapped
that up sooner.
-Now beat it.
-Ator!
Be careful!
-No!
-Huh?
-Hurts, don't it?
-Give my mustache to Trevor!
-Trevor?
-Hey, thanks a lot, Dong.
I'll visit you in
prison and bake
you a rice cake with
a saw in it, buddy.
I mean Thong.
-Father!
Ator!
Are you all right?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
Is "Charles in Charge" over?
Thanks for showing up.
-[Inaudible].
-Thank goodness you're safe.
-Hey, come on.
-Thanks to Ator.
-How about a little sugar
for Ator over here, huh?
-Thong?
-No, it's a dance belt.
-I'll be with you in a minute.
-Your father gave
me the nucleus.
I'm taking it back with me.
-Oh, and, uh, there was some
turkey and stuff in the fridge.
I made myself a sandwich.
Hope you don't mind.
-Mila, I wanted to say that--
-You don't have to say anything.
I know you must fight
evil wherever it occurs.
-My life is too dangerous
to share with you.
-You must follow your destiny.
Alone.
-With Chad.
-Goodbye, Mila.
After I finish, I'll be back.
-And I'll look like
a leather pancake.
-Yes.
-Take care of yourself
and your father.
He needs you.
-Uh, I got go model for
a line of action figures.
I'll see you.
-Watch over them, Thong.
-I think I can do that.
-He is like, so cool.
-Oh.
-Miles O'Keeffe will be
back in "Where Angels Go,
Trouble Follows."
-Hey, feedback.
Neat.
-Lest the nucleus fall
into unscrupulous hands,
and the Earth and all
living creatures be consumed
in a seething cauldron
of annihilation--
-Anybody got a clue?
---Ator destroyed it.
Perhaps in the future,
man would be wise enough
to use this Promethean
[INAUDIBLE].
-Actually, Mrs. O'Leary's
cow kicked it over.
That's how it happened.
-Mankind.
You make me want to vomit.
Go away, just go away.
I'm so sick of you.
Get out of here.
Come on.
-Well, this is neat,
but what the heck does
it have to do with the movie?
-Uh.
Your guess is as good as mine.
I think they ran
out of things to do.
Throw a little Oppenheimer
in here right now.
Hey, I see a president's
face up there.
-I see a bunny.
-How about enough of this?
Let's escape to Wisconsin.
-He looks like he traded in
his hang glider for a horse.
-He probably built that horse,
too, now that I think about it.
-Out of mud and sticks.
-Raised it from a pup.
Beautiful animal, isn't he?
-Hey look, tire tracks!
---inherent goodness of man--
-The inherent dullness of man.
---to do battle.
Wherever man's oppressed--
-Wherever there's kids
laughing because they're hungry
and they know supper's ready.
Whenever there's a cop
beating up on a guy.
---too powerful and
protect it to avoid
his rightful punishment.
He is the guardian of knowledge
and the hope of the future.
-Yeah right.
-Ator, the avenger.
-Huh?
-What?
-Oh, the guardians of
BO all of a sudden.
-No, those are
the screenwriters.
Take your best shot, guys.
-I gotta get something
heavy to throw.
-This is really cute,
these credits here, huh?
-Hey, it's the New
Kids in the Cave.
-Oh.
-You know, they couldn't even
find an exciting enough scene
from their own movie to
show with the credits.
-This looks like the
Jefferson Junior High
production of
"Godspell" that I saw.
-I missed that.
-Uh, oh, those--
[beatboxing]
-No, no, no, no, no, the
mohawk goes the other way.
You look like a turkey.
-Or kind of like
a bath brush, too.
-Yeah.
[Beatboxing]
-Walk like an Egyptian.
Chonk chonk.
-Hey chickenhead.
Hey chickenhead.
-Who said that?
-Heh heh, shh.
-Now where is my shirt?
-Papillon, I need to
borrow some money.
-I think he's looking for James
Franciscus and Charlton Heston.
[Beatboxing]
-Kinda groovy.
-OK, let's get out of
this dog right now.
-Who is it?
-We've gotta go.
-Oh.
-Oh hi.
-Hey, it's Chad and Trevor,
they found each other.
-What?
-What do you want?
Come on, what?
It wasn't that bad.
Was it?
Come on.
-I liked it.
[Growling]
-Look, Booby, when
we send you a film,
they're supposed to be bad.
What do you want from us?
-I mean, we have
it worse than them.
We have to watch you
watching the film.
[Sigh]
-OK look, it's bad enough
that this was clearly
the worst film you
have ever send us,
but it was also filled with
continuity problems to boot.
My colleague Crow
will elucidate.
-Uh, I'll what?
-You'll show them.
-Oh right, right, OK.
Anyway, frame 122'7,
Cambot, bring that up?
A pan of a field, yet
seen clearly in the back,
somebody's been four-wheeling.
OK, next frame please,
2162503, thank you, Cambot.
Forgiving the fact that Ator
is flying a hang glider,
he's doing it over
a modern city!
OK, now the piece de
resistance, Cambot, 2020'3.
OK, during the
raping and pillaging,
a prehistoric caveman
is clearly seen
wearing a pair of Ray Bans.
Who is that behind
the Foster Grants?
It's Ogg!
-Yeah, and what about
Scarecrow's brain?
-Huh?
-What do you want from us?
We're evil!
Evil!
-Yep, I guess you
could say we're
you cut from a different cloth.
-Exactly, Frank.
-You could say we're
more evil than a $3 bill.
-Push the button, Frank.
-Guess you could say the
factory's still open,
but we're making
different stuff now.
-Would you just push the button?
-Push the button.
Guess you could say
we're buying it wholesale
and passing the
savings on to you.
[Theme music]
-Thong, the fish is ready.